<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<MLRH_2022_3_386>
	<OTHER_CITATIONS>
		<ILJ_CITATION></ILJ_CITATION>
		<ILJU_CITATION></ILJU_CITATION>
		<MLJ_CITATION></MLJ_CITATION>
		<MLJU_CITATION></MLJU_CITATION>
		<ILR_CITATION></ILR_CITATION>
		<CLJ_CITATION></CLJ_CITATION>
		<LNS_CITATION></LNS_CITATION>
		<AMR_CITATION></AMR_CITATION>
	</OTHER_CITATIONS>

	<UNREPORTED_CITATION>MLRHU_2022_88</UNREPORTED_CITATION>

	<JUDGMENT_COUNTRY>MALAYSIA</JUDGMENT_COUNTRY>
	<STATE>SELANGOR</STATE>
	<JUDGMENT_LANGUAGE>ENGLISH</JUDGMENT_LANGUAGE>

	<JUDGMENT_NAME>YEE TECK FAH v. LEE CHEE MENG &amp; ANOR</JUDGMENT_NAME>
	<COURT_TYPE>High Court Malaya, Shah Alam</COURT_TYPE>
	<JUDGE_NAME>Tee Geok Hock JC</JUDGE_NAME>
	<JUDGMENT_NUMBER>[Writ Summons No: BA-22NCVC-182-04/2021]</JUDGMENT_NUMBER>
	<JUDGMENT_DATE>10 January 2022</JUDGMENT_DATE>

	<HEADNOTE>

		<CATCHWORDS>
			<p>
				<i>
					<b>
						<SUBJECT_INDEX>Civil Procedure</SUBJECT_INDEX>:
					</b> Costs - Security for costs - Application for security for costs of counterclaim - Fresh allegations of different nature and character than in original claim - Whether this would also involve much longer trial and more costs - Whether application not an abuse of court's process - Whether moderate amount should be allowed as security for costs
				</i>
			</p>
		</CATCHWORDS>

		<p>In the original action, Yee Teck Fah ("Yee TF") in his statement of claim sought, among others, an order for specific performance of the Sale and Purchase Agreement of a bungalow house (asserted to be worth more than RM20 million) from bankrupts Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang ("Lee and Loo"). Yee TF's original action was based on the Sale and Purchase Agreement and related documents. Subsequently, Lee and Loo filed a Defence and Counterclaim against Yee TF and Ong Gek Lin ("Ong GL"). In the Counterclaim, Lee and Loo made numerous allegations against Yee TF and Ong GL, which were quite different in nature and character from those which formed the basis of Yee TF's claims in the original action. Yee TF then applied for security for costs of the Counterclaim in the sum of RM200,000 against Lee and Loo.</p>

		<p>
			<b>Held</b> (allowing the application for security for costs in the amount of RM30,000):
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>(1)</b> There were, on the facts, some allegations in the Counterclaim which were fresh allegations of a different nature and character from those of the defences to Yee TF's claim. In the circumstances, Lee and Loo were the real attackers in the Counterclaim and not merely defending their case against Yee TF's original claim. Moreover, the fact that Lee and Loo had brought in Ong GL as the additional co-defendant in the Counterclaim was evidence of their counter-attack against Ong GL jointly with Yee TF. The numerous allegations of a different nature and character from those of the claim in the original action would also involve a much longer trial and more costs. Further, the application for security for costs in the present action was not an abuse of the court's process. Lee and Loo had failed to give sufficient evidence to show how they would be prejudiced by security for costs of a moderate amount. Thus, a moderate amount of RM30,000 as security for costs in the present case involving a subject-matter worth millions of ringgit would not be oppressive to Lee and Loo nor stifle their pursuit of the Counterclaim. (paras 21-26)
		</p>

		<REFERRED_CASES>
			<p>
				<b>Case(s) referred to:</b>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>Amalgamated Mining Services Pty Ltd v. Warman International Ltd [1988] 19 FCR 324 (refd)</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2006_3_520;">Doree Industries (M) Sdn Bhd &amp; Ors v. Sri Ram &amp; Co &amp; Ors [2006] 3 MLRH 520</LINK>; [2007] 1 MLJ 722; [2007] 1 CLJ 272 (folld)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_1995_2_72;">Faridah Begum Abdullah v. Dato' Michael Chong [1995] 2 MLRH 72</LINK>; [1995] 2 MLJ 404; [1995] 2 CLJ 951; [1995] 2 AMR 1191 (folld)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRHU_2021_2387;">Knit Textiles MFG Sdn Bhd lwn. Asmara International Ltd [2021] MLRHU 2387</LINK> (refd)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2001_4_698;">Luminous Crossroads Sdn Bhd v. Lim Kong Huat Construction [2001] 4 MLRH 698</LINK>; [2002] 5 CLJ 100; [2001] 4 AMR 4861 (refd)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>Maatschappij voor Fondsenbezit v. Shell Transport and Trading Co [1923] 2 KB 166 (folld)</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRHU_2012_1296;">Mas Anita Abdullah v. Lew Wai Koung [2012] MLRHU 1296</LINK>; [2013] 3 CLJ 737 (refd)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>Sir Lindsay Parkinson &amp; Co Ltd v. Triplan Ltd [1973] 2 All ER 273 (refd)</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2021_2_236;">Tan Bon Kiat v. Lau Kok Guan @ Low Kok Guan &amp; Ors [2021] 2 MLRH 236</LINK> (refd)
				</i>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>Willey v. Synan [1935] 54 CLR 175 (refd)</i>
			</p>
		</REFERRED_CASES>

		<REFERRED_LEGISLATIONS>
			<p>
				<b>Legislation referred to:</b>
			</p>

			<p>
				<LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_2012_205;23;SN1.;;">Rules of Court 2012, O 23 r 1</LINK>
			</p>

			<p>
				<LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_1980_050;23.;;">Rules of the High Court 1980, O 23 r 1</LINK>
			</p>
		</REFERRED_LEGISLATIONS>

		<COUNSELS>
			<p>
				<b>Counsel:</b>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i></i>
				<PLAINTIFF>
					For the plaintiff: <PLAINTIFF_NAME>Yee Teck Fah</PLAINTIFF_NAME> (<PLAINTIFF_NAME>Yee Mi Kenn</PLAINTIFF_NAME> with him); <FIRMS_NAME>M/s Yee Teck Fah &amp; Co</FIRMS_NAME>
				</PLAINTIFF>
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>
					<RESPONDENT>
						For the respondent: <RESPONDENT_NAME>Muhammad Azwar Abdul Manab</RESPONDENT_NAME> (<RESPONDENT_NAME>Muhammad Azrul Haziq Khirullah</RESPONDENT_NAME> with him); <FIRMS_NAME>M/s Azwar &amp; Partners</FIRMS_NAME>
					</RESPONDENT>
				</i>
			</p>
		</COUNSELS>

		<VERDICT>
			<p>
				<i>[Allowing the application for security for costs in the amount of RM30,000.]</i>
			</p>
		</VERDICT>

	</HEADNOTE>

	<PARTY>
		<PARTY_JNO>[Writ Summons No: BA-22NCVC-182-04/2021]</PARTY_JNO>
		<PLAINTIFF>
			<NAME>Yee Teck Fah [IC No: 570530-10-6115]</NAME>
		</PLAINTIFF>
		<DEFENDANT>
			<NAME>Lee Chee Meng [IC No: 620625-05-5165]</NAME>
			<NAME>Loo Kim Lang [IC No: 631025-08-5794]</NAME>
		</DEFENDANT>
	</PARTY>

	<JUDGMENT>

		<p>
			<b>JUDGMENT</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>
				<NAME>Tee Geok Hock JC</NAME>
			</b>:
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>Introduction</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[1]</b> In the original action, the plaintiff/Yee Teck Fah (Yee TF) sued the bankrupts Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang for the specific performance and transfer of a bungalow house which the defendants asserted to be worth more than RM20 million.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[2]</b> In the counterclaim, the bankrupts Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang (Lee and Loo) alleged <i>inter alia</i> that: (a) Yee TF as their solicitor entered into all transaction documents in respect of their bungalow house pursuant to the fiduciary relationship and as constructive trustee for them; (b) the Sale and Purchase Agreement was void for want of consideration; (c) the transaction documents entered into by them on Yee TF's advice as solicitor, is a sham transaction; (d) the transaction documents were entered into upon Yee TF's advice as solicitor in order to avoid actions by creditors and was entered into in breach of professional duty, conflict of interest, or pursuant to fraud, cheating, misrepresentation, breach of trust; (e) the solicitor took advantage of their situation and acted in breach of professional duty; (f) Yee TF acted in breach of fiduciary duty; (g) Yee TF does not come to court with clean hands or <i>bona fide</i>. Lee and Loo counterclaimed for: (i) declaration that Yee TF and wife committed fraud, cheating and/or deception; (ii) Yee TF and Ong GL committed negligence, omission and/or cheating against them; (iii) a declaration that the Sale and Purchase Agreement dated 15 May 2015 is null and void and be set aside; (iv) a declaration that the Power of Attorney dated 15 May 2015 is null and void and be set aside; (v) a declaration that the letter dated 22 May 2015 on confirmation of full payment is null and void and be set aside; (vi) monetary damages in the sum of RM4,000,000; (vii) aggravated damages; (viii) exemplary damages; (ix) punitive damages; (x) costs etc. These claims and allegations were denied by Yee TF.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[3]</b> In the counterclaim proceedings, Yee Teck Fah ("Yee TF") the 1st defendant in the counterclaim (who is also the plaintiff in the original action) applied for security for costs of counterclaim in the sum of RM200,000 against Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang ("Lee and Loo"), the plaintiffs in the counterclaim (who are also the defendants in the original action).
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[4]</b> After having considered the affidavits and heard the submissions, this Court on 29 November 2021 ordered to pay security for costs in the amount of RM30,000.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[5]</b> Being dissatisfied with the said decision of security for costs, Lee and Loo has appealed against the said decision notwithstanding the fact that the amount of security for costs in a small fraction of the values of the subject- matters in the counterclaim.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>Background Facts</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[6]</b> In the original action, Yee TF in his statement of claim seeks, among others, an order for specific performance of the Sale and Purchase Agreement of Geran No 212024 Lot No 63370 Bandar Glenmarie, Daerah Petaling, Negeri Selangor ("the said Property") from Lee and Loo.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[7]</b> Yee TF's original action is based on the Sale and Purchase Agreement and related documents.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[8]</b> On 27 July 2021, Lee and Loo filed a Defence and Counterclaim against Yee TF as the 1st defendant (in the counterclaim) and Ong Gek Lin, as the 2nd defendant (in the counterclaim).
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[9]</b> In the counterclaim, Lee and Loo made numerous allegations against Yee TF and Ong GL, and these allegations in the counterclaim are quite different in nature and character from the those which form the basis of Yee TF's claims in the original action.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>Law On Security For Costs</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[10]</b> <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_2012_205;23;SN1.;;">Order 23 r 1 of the Rules of Court 2012</LINK> provides that the court may order security for costs if having regard to all the circumstances of the case the court finds it just to do so. The Court is not precluded from ordering security for costs merely by reason of bankruptcy or impecuniosity. This principle of law was applied in the cases mentioned hereinafter.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[11]</b> In <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2006_3_520;">
				<i>Doree Industries (M) Sdn Bhd &amp; Ors v. Sri Ram &amp; Co &amp; Ors</i> [2006] 3 MLRH 520
			</LINK>; [2007] 1 MLJ 722; [2007] 1 CLJ 272, the plaintiffs had filed a claim against the defendants seeking for damages, the value of the insured sum, injunction, and certain declaration in this suit as well as in four other suits all at the Ipoh High Court. The 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs were the directors of the 1st plaintiff and it was against these three plaintiffs that the defendants were asking for security for costs. The 1st plaintiff had been wound up on 12 March 2001 and a sanction was given by the Jabatan Insolvensi on 1 April 2004 under the provisions of the <LINK HREF="LegislationMainDisplayed.aspx?MY_ACTS_1973_125;;">Companies Act 1965</LINK> for it to proceed with the claim. In granting the sanction, the Jabatan Insolvensi had asked for a sum of RM2,000 to be deposited as security for costs for all the five suits filed by the plaintiffs. The 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs were declared bankrupt on 12 March 2002 and 29 January 2002 respectively and remained so at the time of the application by the defendants. The defendant had stated in the affidavit in support of the application that both the 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs had given different addresses at different times. The learned deputy registrar had ordered the sum of RM20,000 against the 1st plaintiff and RM10,000 against each of the 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs. The amount was against each of the applicant in each application and in its totality the 1st plaintiff would have to fork out RM200,000 against the ten applications while the second and third plaintiff would each have to provide RM100,000 as security for all the ten applications filed against them. The 1st, 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs and the 4th defendant appealed. The four defendants had sought for security for costs against the 1st, 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs in the sum of between RM250,000 and RM300,000. The 4th defendant's solicitors had also put up a draft bill of costs for RM250,000. In dismissing the appeals the Court held:
		</p>
		<blockquote>
			<p>(1) It was established and admitted that the 1st plaintiff was in liquidation. Accordingly, it was for plaintiff to satisfy the court why security for costs should not be ordered. There were no sufficient grounds to satisfy the court why security for costs should not be ordered. The fact that the 1st plaintiff had paid RM2,000 as security for costs to the Jabatan Insolvensi was insufficient ground why security for costs should not be ordered. His plea that the 1st plaintiff was in liquidation and that the other two plaintiffs were bankrupts and therefore should not be further burdened by ordering security for costs clearly was an admission that the 1st plaintiff was unable to pay the costs. Further, an application for security for costs in the instant case was not an abuse of the court's process. The plaintiff had failed to give sufficient evidence to show how it would be prejudiced by the application. There was not an iota of evidence that could tilt the scale in their favour and there was also nothing in the affidavit to indicate that the plaintiffs would as a result of this order suffer injustice or that it would stifle its claim or that the order would be oppressive. Worse still, there was nothing in the affidavit in reply to show its ability to pay the costs in the event it was to fail in its claim against the defendants.</p>

			<p>
				(2) <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_1980_050;23.;;">Order 23 r 1 of the Rules of the High Court 1980</LINK> is not a carte blanche provision empowering the court to order security for costs in all cases where the plaintiff's address is not stated in the writ or other originating process or is incorrectly stated. To order for security under the said rule the court must have regard to all the circumstances of the case and that the court thinks it is just to do so. Having different addresses per se is not a ground as envisaged under <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_1980_050;23.;;">O 23</LINK> and there was no evidence to suggest that the plaintiffs had been changing addresses to evade the consequence of the litigation. It was also not suggested that the plaintiffs' address in the writ was incorrectly stated. In the same token there was also no plausible reason or explanation given by the plaintiffs as to the existence or usage of the different addresses.
			</p>

			<p>(3) Both the 2nd and 3rd plaintiffs had been declared bankrupts and the court could understand the defendant's apprehension over the plaintiffs' ability to meet any order as to costs which the court may make. However, it is trite that the plaintiffs' impecuniosity by itself is not a sufficient ground for the court to make an order for security for costs.</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>
			<b>[12]</b> In <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_1995_2_72;">
				<i>Faridah Begum Abdullah v. Dato' Michael Chong</i> [1995] 2 MLRH 72
			</LINK>; [1995] 2 MLJ 404; [1995] 2 CLJ 951; [1995] 2 AMR 1191, the court in ordering the plaintiff to pay RM15,000 into court as security for costs held <i>inter alia</i> that "the mere bankruptcy or impecuniosity of a plaintiff is not a sufficient ground for ordering security for costs against it. On the other hand, the court is not precluded from ordering security for costs under <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_1980_050;23.;;">O 23 of the RHC</LINK> merely by reason of the plaintiff's bankruptcy or impecuniosity. Therefore, the court may order security for costs if, having regard to all the circumstances of the case, the court finds it just to do so."
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[13]</b> Based on <i>Doree Industries (M) Sdn Bhd &amp; Ors v. Sri Ram &amp; Co &amp; Ors (supra)</i> and <i>Faridah Begum Abdullah v. Dato'Michael Chong (supra)</i> the mere fact that the claimant is insolvent or under bankruptcy is not a sufficient ground to refuse to order security for costs.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[14]</b> Furthermore, in <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRHU_2012_1296;">
				<i>Mas Anita Abdullah v. Lew Wai Koung</i> [2012] MLRHU 1296
			</LINK>; [2013] 3 CLJ 737 the Court in allowing security for costs of RM40,000.00 had this to say "[7] There is no legal requirement that the defendant gives a detailed bill of costs before he can make this application. The rules regarding the exercise of the court's discretionary powers to order security for costs are not inflexible or rigid (see <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_1995_2_72;">
				<i>Faridah Begum Abdullah v. Dato' Michael Chong</i> [1995] 2 MLRH 72
			</LINK>; [1995] 2 MLJ 404; [1995] 2 CLJ 951; [1995] 2 AMR 1191). The amount for the security costs which I ordered is a reasonable sum ie, RM40,000 and not RM60,000 as applied for by the defendant. According to the defendant, the amount of RM60,000 is less than 10% of the amount claimed by the plaintiff for the losses she suffered when the defendant took possession of the premises occupied by the plaintiff. The amount of RM40,000 is therefore an even lower percentage than 10% of the plaintiff's claim. I do not think that this amount is excessive or oppressive to the plaintiff. In fact, this amount is much less than the security for costs that this court has ordered for several other cases."
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[15]</b> In <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2021_2_236;">
				<i>Tan Bon Kiat v. Lau Kok Guan @ Low Kok Guan &amp; Ors</i> [2021] 2 MLRH 236
			</LINK>, the learned Evrol Mariette Peters JC considered the argument that an order for security for costs contravenes the provisions of the <LINK HREF="LegislationMainDisplayed.aspx?MY_ACTS_1988_360;;">Insolvency Act 1967</LINK> and held at paras 10 to 12:
		</p>
		<blockquote>
			<p>
				"[10] In any event, the sanction obtained from the Official Assignee, must necessarily mean that just as much as the plaintiff is not prevented from proceeding with the Civil Suit, he should also be subjected to the full spectrum of the defendants' Defence, which includes the defendants' rights under <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_2012_205;23.;;">O 23 of the Rules of Court</LINK> for security for costs, which in my view, could not be denied by the plaintiff, simply because he is a bankrupt.
			</p>

			<p>
				[11] That being the case, the plaintiff's contention that this application contravenes the provisions of the <LINK HREF="LegislationMainDisplayed.aspx?MY_ACTS_1988_360;;">Insolvency Act 1967</LINK>, is misconceived.
			</p>

			<p>
				[12] Furthermore, <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_2012_205;23;SN1.;;">O 23 r 1 of the Rules of Court</LINK> contains no prohibition in itself to the making of an order for security for costs against a bankrupt. In fact, what is stated in <LINK HREF="legislationSectiondisplayed.aspx?MY_PUAS_2012_205;23;SN1.;;">O 23 r 1</LINK> is that the discretion of making such order remains with the Court, "having regard to all the circumstances of the case'.
			</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>
			<b>[16]</b> In <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRH_2001_4_698;">
				<i>Luminous Crossroads Sdn Bhd v. Lim Kong Huat Construction</i> [2001] 4 MLRH 698
			</LINK>; [2002] 5 CLJ 100; [2001] 4 AMR 4861, the High Court adopted the ratio of the English Court of Appeal in <i>Sir Lindsay Parkinson &amp; Co Ltd v. Triplan Ltd</i> [1973] 2 All ER 273. The English Court set out the circumstances which the Court could consider in deciding on whether to order security for costs. The said circumstances include:
		</p>
		<blockquote>
			<p>
				(1) whether the claim is <i>bona fide</i> with good prospects of success;
			</p>

			<p>(2) whether there is an admission on the pleadings or elsewhere that the money is due;</p>

			<p>(3) whether there is payment into court of a substantial sum of money (not merely a payment into court to get rid of a nuisance claim) (O 22A r 5(1));</p>

			<p>(4) whether the application for security for costs is being used to stifle a genuine claim; and</p>

			<p>(5) whether the want of means of the plaintiff is a result of the conduct of the defendant.</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>
			<b>[17]</b> The High Court in <LINK HREF="case_notes/showcase.aspx?pageid=MLRHU_2021_2387;">
				<i>Knit Textiles MFG Sdn Bhd lwn. Asmara International Ltd</i> [2021] MLRHU 2387
			</LINK> dismissed the application for security for costs in relation to the Counterclaim. The Court referred to the decision of the Australian High Court in <i>Willey v. Synan</i> [1935] 54 CLR 175 which held that "that the defendant should be treated as a defendant throughout, and not be required to give security for cost of the cross-bill, which, in truth is merely defensive." The Court also referred to the decision of the Australian Federal Court in <i>Amalgamated Mining Services Pty Ltd v. Warman International Ltd</i> [1988] 19 FCR 324 which held that "The court always, as I understand, endeavours to be guided by the substance and not by the form of the matter, and orders security for costs against the foreign attacker, not against the foreigner defending himself or his property from attack".
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[18]</b> The rationale of a security for costs "is to give costs protection to a defendant who is forced into litigation at the election of someone else.": see Deemster Corlett's <i>ex tempore</i> judgment on 20 January 2013 in Summary Court in the case of <i>Flexton Limited v. Breeze</i> (unreported). As such, when considering an application for security for costs of counterclaim, this Court ought to identify the "attacker" in the claim and counterclaim proceedings and the "attacker" does not necessarily mean the party who makes the counterclaim.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[19]</b> The approach of identifying the true attacker was taken by the English Court of Appeal in <i>Maatschappij voor Fondsenbezit v. Shell Transport and Trading Co</i> [1923] 2 KB 166. In the judgment of Scrutton LJ, the Court held as follows:
		</p>
		<blockquote>
			<p>"The position, I think, extends to every case where the person against whom security is sought is really defending himself against attack, even if he be nominally a plaintiff, but really defending himself against defendants' previous action against him."</p>
		</blockquote>

		<p>
			<b>Analysis And Decision In The Present Case</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[20]</b> In our present case, the bankrupts Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang in their counterclaim alleged <i>inter alia</i> that: (a) Yee TF as their solicitor entered into all transaction documents in respect of their bungalow house pursuant to the fiduciary relationship and as constructive trustee for them; (b) the Sale and Purchase Agreement was void for want of consideration; (c) the transaction documents entered into by them on Yee TF's advice as solicitor, is a sham transaction; (d) the transaction documents were entered into upon Yee TF's advice as solicitor in order to avoid actions by creditors and was entered into in breach of professional duty, conflict of interest, or pursuant to fraud, cheating, misrepresentation, breach of trust; (e) the solicitor took advantage of their situation and acted in breach of professional duty; (f) Yee TF acted in breach of fiduciary duty; and (g) Yee TF does not come to court with clean hands or <i>bona fide</i>. Lee and Loo counterclaimed for (i) declaration that Yee TF and wife committed fraud, cheating and/or deception; (ii) Yee TF and Ong GL committed negligence, omission and/or cheating against them; (iii) a declaration that the Sale and Purchase Agreement dated 15 May 2015 is null and void and be set aside; (iv) a declaration that the Power of Attorney dated 15 May 2015 is null and void and be set aside; (v) a declaration that the letter dated 22 May 2015 on confirmation of full payment is null and void and be set aside; (vi) monetary damages in the sum of RM4,000,000; (vii) aggravated damages; (viii) exemplary damages; (ix) punitive damages; (x) costs etc.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[21]</b> This Court has perused and analysed the allegations in the Defence and Counterclaim of Lee and Loo (encl 19), in particular paras 49 to 66 under the heading "Counterclaim". While some of the allegations in Lee and Loo's counterclaim are of the nature and effect of defence to Yee TF's claim in the original action, there are also some allegations in Lee and Loo's counterclaim which are fresh allegations of different nature and character from those of defences to Yee TF's claim. Such allegations in Lee and Loo's counterclaim include allegations regarding Yee TF's acts and conduct in his professional capacity as solicitor. Also, the counterclaim for monetary damages of RM4,000,000, aggravated damages, exemplary damages and/or punitive damages are of different nature and character from those of defences to Yee TF's claim.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[22]</b> In the circumstances, this Court finds that in respect of allegations in the counterclaim of different nature and character from those of defences to Yee TF's claim and in respect of the of different nature and character from those of defences to Yee TF's claim, Lee and Loo are the real attackers in the counterclaim and not merely defending their case against Yee TF's original claim.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[23]</b> Moreover, the fact that Lee and Loo have brought in Ong GL as the additional co-defendant in the counterclaim is an evidence of their counterattack against Ong GL jointly with Yee TF.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[24]</b> The numerous allegations of different nature and character from those of the claim in the original action would also involve much longer trial and more costs.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[25]</b> Further, the application for security for costs in the present action is not an abuse of the court's process. Lee and Loo have failed to give sufficient evidence to show how they would be prejudiced by a security for costs of a moderate amount. There was also nothing in the affidavit to indicate that Lee and Loo would, as a result of this order for security for costs of a moderate amount, suffer injustice or that it would stifle their claim or that the order would be oppressive. Worse still, there was nothing in the affidavit in reply to show their ability to pay the costs in the event they were to fail in their counterclaim against Yee TF (the plaintiff in the original action and 1st defendant in the counterclaim) and Ong GL (the 2nd defendant in the counterclaim). However, it is trite that impecuniosity by itself is not a sufficient ground for the court not to make an order for security for costs.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[26]</b> In the entire circumstances, this Court finds and holds that some amount of security for costs ought to be ordered against Lee and Loo. In order not to let the huge amount of security of costs become a stifling of Lee and Loo's defence in the original action, this Court assesses the reasonable amount of security for costs of the counterclaim at RM30,000, which is just a small fraction of the amount of RM200,000 applied for by Yee TF. This Court considers that a moderate amount of RM30,000 as security for costs in the present case involving a subject matter worth millions of ringgit would not be oppressive to Lee and Loo nor stifle Lee and Loo's pursuit of counterclaim in the present case.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>Conclusion</b>
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[27]</b> In conclusion, this Court on 29 November 2021 allowed Yee TF's application for security for costs of counterclaim and hereby orders Lee Chee Meng and Loo Kim Lang to provide security for costs in the amount of RM30,000/= to be deposited in the joint names of the plaintiff's solicitor and the defendants' solicitor as joint stakeholders within 14 days from the date of service of this sealed order.
		</p>

		<p>
			<b>[28]</b> Costs of this application in encl 39 were assessed at RM4,000/=, subject to allocator, to be paid by the defendants (Lee and Loo) to the plaintiff (Yee TF). However, prayer (b) of encl 39 is not allowed. There is no stay of proceedings in this action. Liberty is given to either party to apply in the event of the defendants' failure to provide the said security for costs within the stipulated time.
		</p>

	</JUDGMENT>
</MLRH_2022_3_386>